# Anandraj Elumalai

# Software Developer

A Full Stack Developer with over 6 years of experience specializing in Software development in Banking and Finance (Cards and E-Payments) domain. Strong aspiration in designing and developing Cloud Native Applications. Interested in a challenging technical career with continuous learning and honing skills as passion.

anandrajek@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/anandrajelu

+919551553005

anandraj.dev

github.com/anandrajelu

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

# **PayPal**

Software Engineer 2

09/2021 - Present

Payment Card Platform

Self acquiring and processing of card transactions

- PayPal has started acquiring and processing debit & credit cards in a wider goal to reduce overall transaction expense. This initiative will greatly reduce the various fees associated with card processing & gives merchants huge relief.
- Developed API, batch applications for card transactions **processing** & secure file transmission with external sources.
- Involved in review, testing, ramp up and production bug fixes which reduced the estimated ready to market rate by 15%.

Software Developer, Specialist

10/2019 - 09/2021

Product - Zelle

Fraud Machine Learning Model - FML Model

- Fraud Machine Learning Model is an advanced risk detection strategy for an electronic transaction. Every transaction will be scored based on the risk evaluation and various attributes of the transaction. The ML model provides a robust policy to handle fraudulent transactions using the most recent and current training data.
- Improved performance of the traversal logic by using Binary Tree structure which mitigated the time complexity by 40%.
- Built Test, production simulation models for the FML Model.

#### Wipro

**Project Engineer** 

11/2015 - 10/2018

Client - Mastercard

Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard (PCI DSS)

- PCI DSS is a set of security standards designed to ensure that all companies that accept, process, store or transmit credit card information maintain a secure environment. A new security module CSP - Cryptographic Security Protocol was created and restructured entire PIN processing system to adhere to the standards.
- Major contributor to migration from current encryption standards by switching to CSP modules.

#### **EDUCATION**

**B.E. Computer Science and Engineering** Veltech Hightech Engineering College

06/2011 - 01/2015

Chennai, India

Final Year Project

 Created Enterprise Management Application as my Final year project using HTML, Java and MongoDB.

### **SKILLS**

Java	
Spring Boot	• • • • •
Spring Batch	• • • • •
REST APIs	• • • • •
Microservices	$\bullet$ $\bullet$ $\bullet$ $\circ$
ReactJs	$\bullet$ $\bullet$ $\bullet$ $\circ$
Relational Databases	$\bullet$ $\bullet$ $\bullet$ $\circ$
No-SQL Databases	

### **CERTIFICATIONS**

**AWS Certified Developer Associate Amazon Web Services** 

Score

• **973**/1000

02/2021 - 02/2024

### **ORGANIZATIONS**

PayPal (09/2021)

Software Engineer

Fiserv (10/2018 - 09/2021)

Software Developer

Wipro (11/2015 - 10/2018)

Project Engineer

# SPOKEN LANGUAGES

English

Full Professional Proficiency

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

Limited Working Proficiency

#### INTERESTS

Active player in LeetCode.com and Codechef.com which conducts monthly coding challenges.

Learning new

technologies/libraries/algorithms/architectures